<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quotes I like</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/quotes/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/quotes/quotes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;It ain&amp;rsquo;t what you don&amp;rsquo;t know that gets you into trouble. It&amp;rsquo;s what you know for sure that just ain&amp;rsquo;t so.&amp;rsquo; - &amp;lsquo;The Big Short&amp;rsquo;
&amp;lsquo;A poor workman blames his tools&amp;rsquo; - British Proverb
&amp;lsquo;For a successful technology, reality must take precedence over public relations, for nature cannot be fooled.&amp;rsquo; - Personal observations on the reliability of the Shuttle by R. P. Feynman
&amp;lsquo;A delayed game is eventually good, but a rushed game is forever bad&amp;rsquo; - Shigeru Miyamoto</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 200 Year Old Buckle and Button</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/dirtfishin/things_in_the_vermont_dirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/dirtfishin/things_in_the_vermont_dirt/</guid>
      <description>I found both of these relics on the same day in April of 2016 along the edge of an old road. They were about 75 feet apart from each other.
Both items appear to be from the late 1700&amp;rsquo;s and were likely lost by the first generation of settlers in Walden, Vermont.
It is my intention to donate these items to the Walden Historical Committee.
Front View
Rear View The button is 30 [mm] in diameter and is made of a brass alloy called tombac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bayley-Hazen Military Road</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/dirtfishin/bayley_hazen_military_road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/dirtfishin/bayley_hazen_military_road/</guid>
      <description>I have always been fascinated by this Revolutionary War era military road. Below is a description of the Walden portion of the route written by Olive &amp;amp; Maurice Eddy in 1958/59.
The Bayley-Hazen Military Road - Town of Walden
Cover</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Touch of Applesoft BASIC</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/books/applesoft_basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/books/applesoft_basic/</guid>
      <description>A Touch of Applesoft BASIC came with the Apple IIc Plus that I excitedly received early in the AM on Christmas day in 1988. Due to games like Oregon Trail and Think Quick! I am certain that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even open it until several years later. Before reading this book I did not understand that it was practical for a normal person to write a program and run it on a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started in Electronics</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/books/getting_started_in_electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/books/getting_started_in_electronics/</guid>
      <description>I aquired Getting Started in Electronics at the local Radio Shack in the mid 1990&amp;rsquo;s. It taught me the difference between series and parallel circuits and how different electrical components function. Mr. Mims&amp;rsquo; handwritten text and diagrams made it less intimidating to learn about this complex subject.
The last chapter in the book has many projects and I successfully built the one called &amp;lsquo;Mini Radio Transmitter&amp;rsquo; which simply sent an adjustable tone to a nearby radio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Measure VSWR of an Antenna Using a RTL-SDR</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/amateurradio/diy_2m_yagi_measure_vswr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/amateurradio/diy_2m_yagi_measure_vswr/</guid>
      <description>I was able to measure the VSWR of my Yagi antenna using a random noise source, directional coupler, and RTL-SDR.
A program called rtl_power_fftw was used to measure the noise signal reflected back to the RTL-SDR by the antenna. The VSWR was calculated and plotted using Python in a Jupyter Notebook. It shows a VSWR of about 1.5 over most of the 2m band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Birch Tree in Winter</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/art/water_color_birch_tree_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/art/water_color_birch_tree_2020/</guid>
      <description>The result of an attempt at watercolors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulate a DIY Yagi Antenna for 2m VHF</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/amateurradio/diy_2m_yagi_simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/amateurradio/diy_2m_yagi_simulation/</guid>
      <description>I decided to build an simple Yagi antenna for my APRS I-gate.
I ended up on the yagi design because it helps lower the noise floor at my location by reducing the signal from a broadcast FM station located nearby.
I simulated the antenna using a program called xnec2c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Day with Diesel</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/art/dieselremembered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/art/dieselremembered/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this after the death of our beloved Great Dane named Diesel.
Last Day with Diesel free of collar and of leash he paused to keep the pace,
we watched with apprehension fearing pain upon his face
he stood and looked around him that gray and misty day,
in a field, his domain, that had just been cleared of hay
he paused for a moment, while the breeze brought him a smell,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I tend to use open source stuff</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/opensource/whyopensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/opensource/whyopensource/</guid>
      <description>When possible, I gravitate towards open source options when choosing software or hardware for the following reasons:
I don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with licenses or keys There are usually multiple options - I can try them all and pick the one I like best My data isn&amp;rsquo;t held hostage by a proprietary format At work, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to ask permission to use a piece of software If it breaks there is usually more information available to aid in the fix There is often better support or at least more information on how it was built or functions Using, installing, and maintaining it is a challenge and this forces me to learn new things I can participate in improvements Easier to understand the results of a given program Can have the same software on all of my computers </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got started in open source</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/opensource/howopensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/opensource/howopensource/</guid>
      <description>My journey into open source began with the Mozilla Firefox Browser. This program is what put the concept of open source software in my head.
After becoming more aware of open source, I gave the Ubuntu operating system a try and I was astounded at how little RAM was used, and how much better file transfer over USB worked.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using GNU/Linux daily since about 2006 and I now use open source stuff as much as practically possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off Past Canaan</title>
      <link>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/art/off_past_canaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caseyjamesdavis.github.io/hobbies/art/off_past_canaan/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this for my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s memorial service. Both of my grandparents enjoyed snowmobiling from the late 60&amp;rsquo;s until their passing. The above photo and many childhood memories were inspiration for this poem.
Off Past Canaan The clock chimed high from the southern wall,
signaling the end of the dinner call.
The television is off, the suit is found,
the wood stove is stuffed so it won&amp;rsquo;t go out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
